<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chuan Zhang on Chuan Zhang</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chuan Zhang on Chuan Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:27:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of intelligent cyber-physical systems on the decarbonization of energy</title>
      <link>/publication/2020_intelligent_decarbonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2020_intelligent_decarbonization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Zero America Project</title>
      <link>/project/net-zero-america-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/net-zero-america-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To avoid the worst impacts of climate change, global emissions of CO2 must fall to zero by roughly mid-century and go net negative soon thereafter. Rich, developed nations like the United States have the means, and arguably the obligation, to lead the pace of transition. What will it take for the United States to build a net-zero emissions energy system? Why is a 100% carbon-free electricity system pivotal to this challenge? What role do technologies like wind, solar, batteries, nuclear, and carbon capture play in this future? Prof. Jenkins will summarize the decarbonization challenge in the American context, drawing on recent publications and preliminary findings of Princeton&amp;rsquo;s Net-Zero America Project, which is mapping pathways for the United States to reach net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Useful Links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cpree.princeton.edu/events/getting-zero-can-america-transition-net-zero-emissions-energy-system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Getting to Zero: Can America Transition to a Net-Zero Emissions Energy System?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://acee.princeton.edu/research/energy-systems-analysis-group/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Energy Systems Analysis Group (ESAG), Princeton University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cmi.princeton.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Carbon Mitigation Initiative (CMI), Princeton University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evolved.energy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Evolved Energy Research, Near-term advising on long-term energy transition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging energy system decarbonisation through AI</title>
      <link>/post/digitalization_energy_transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/digitalization_energy_transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Integrating digital tools into the world’s energy systems could reduce carbon emissions by more than 50 per cent, a recent review has found. Decarbonising the world’s energy systems is a crucial part of mitigating climate change through the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions. While decarbonisation is non-negotiable if climate breakdown is to be halted, it must be balanced with ensuring economic stability and a smooth transition to sustainable energy. Digital technologies such as big data, machine learning and the Internet of Things hold immense potential to help us meet this challenge. Their applications range from helping to reduce our power bills by employing smart meters in the home, to assisting with peer-to-peer energy trading between power stations via blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An international team of researchers from the UK, USA, Switzerland and Singapore found that while the existing digital technologies have numerous and effective applications when considered individually, the potential reduction of carbon emissions is multiplied when they are combined. Such combinations are called cyber-physical systems – interacting networks of physical infrastructure and computers that allow for smarter analysis, decision-making and optimisation of energy systems. Introducing artificial intelligence (AI) into these cyber-physical systems can lead to even more carbon savings (a total of 20 per cent with only cyber-physical systems and an extra 30 per cent when AI is included). This combination of technologies creates what is dubbed “intelligent cyber-physical systems”; benefits include more resilient infrastructure and operational flexibility, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forecasting of particular renewable energies is one good example of an intelligent cyber-physical system. The wind and solar energy sectors have seen much growth and while the price of these technologies has reduced, the intermittent nature of this type of power has limited their application. The integration of backup energy systems (natural gas plants, for example) or energy storage technologies is required. Intelligent cyber-physical technologies, in particular machine learning, could help with this integration through improved forecasting of solar and wind variability. Other large energy systems such as power plants can also benefit. When applied to carbon capture and storage plants, for example, these technologies can convert operational data into actionable intelligence, thereby reducing costs and improving energy efficiency through improved processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MACC.png&#34; alt=&#34;Impact of CPS technologies on the marginal abatement cost of selected decarbonization technologies in energy transition&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of particular importance in this work is a revised marginal abatement cost curve (MACC). MACCs illustrate both the cost and potential of various carbon dioxide reduction strategies and are used by policy makers to assess which to pursue. The integration of cyber-physical systems is a substantial update to the MACC and further establishes it as an indispensable tool for those working on decarbonisation. Cyber-physical systems, especially those combined with AI, provide the much-needed boost required for countries to meet their decarbonisation and emissions targets. It is now up to policy makers to take this forward by incentivising the deployment of these technologies to combat climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reference&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oliver Inderwildi, Chuan Zhang, Xiaonan Wang, and Markus Kraft. The Impact of Intelligent Cyber-Physical Systems on the Decarbonization of Energy, &lt;em&gt;Energy &amp;amp; Environmental Science&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 13, 2020, Pages 744-771, DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/C9EE01919G&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1039/C9EE01919G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PJM Grid Modelling</title>
      <link>/project/pjm-decarbonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pjm-decarbonization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to the national decarbonization strategy mentioned in NZAP, a growing number of states and Independent System Operator (ISO) are pledging to reduce emission deeply as well.  To explore what technologies, policies, market designs and planning strategies will increase the likelihood that state and ISO can decarbonize their electricity supply; we have conducted a project assessing the role of New Jersey (NJ) in the deep decarbonization of PJM gird, which is the regional transmission organization responsible for electricity supply of 13 states in upper east coast of US. In this project, we strive to understand understanding how to maximize benefits and minimize costs associated with the deployment of 3500 MW of offshore wind (OSW) electricity generating capacity to be installed off the NJ coast. In the project, we first identify the optimal backbone transmission requirement to accommodate NJ’s projected 3500 MW of OSW, and then identify interregional backbone transmission requirements to accommodate 15000 MW of OSW projected for PJM. In the second step, we use the planned OSW resources, together with transmission configurations identified in step 1, as inputs to simulations of the evolution of the supply resource mix (including capacity retirements and additions), to assessments of wholesale market prices and revenues expected to accrue to OSW resources, and to emission reductions estimates. We use GenX, an electricity capacity expansion model in Julia, to study the evolution of the resource mix and simulate wholesale market outcomes. Since the evolution of the resource mix substantially depends on capacity factors and capital cost of generation resources, higher capacity factors justify investment in higher capital cost resources. In that case, technology-cost sensitivity analysis is conducted: in baseline scenarios, the cost of OSW is based on middle-range values from annual technology baseline of NREL; in high/low technology cost cases, we varied that to low-range and high-range respectively. Moreover, the change of electrification, in particular heat pump for residential heating and electric vehicles, is investigated in the study as well. Finally, we evaluate the sensitivity of our assessments to anticipated market design enhancements, including fast-start pricing in the energy market and clean Minimum Offer Pricing Rule (clean-MOPR). Using electricity market simulation tool  (EMST), a custom-built modeling package (written in CPLEX and MATLAB), we manage to integrate day-ahead, intra-day, and real-time unit commitment and economic dispatch optimization models to faithfully replicate day-ahead and real-time energy markets and grid operations in scaled version representative of PJM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Useful Links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://acee.princeton.edu/research/energy-systems-analysis-group/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Energy Systems Analysis Group (ESAG), Princeton University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tlo.mit.edu/technologies/genx-configurable-capacity-expansion-model&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GENX, Configurable capacity expansion model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.pjm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PJM 101, the basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling low-carbon transition of PJM energy system: data and approach</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_acee_annual_meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 11:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_acee_annual_meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitalization and Energy Transition</title>
      <link>/project/digitalization-and-energy-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/digitalization-and-energy-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The decarbonisation of energy provision is key to managing global greenhouse gas emissions and hence mitigating climate change. Digital technologies such as big data, machine learning, and the Internet of Things are receiving more and more attention as they can aid the decarbonisation process while requiring limited investments. The orchestration of these novel technologies, so-called cyber-physical systems (CPS), provides further, synergetic effects that increase efficiency of energy provision and industrial production, thereby optimising economic feasibility and environmental impact. This comprehensive review article assesses the current as well as the potential impact of digital technologies within CPS on the decarbonisation of energy systems. Ad-hoc calculation for selected applications of CPS and its subsystems estimates not only the economic impact but also the emission reduction potential. This assessment clearly shows that digitalisation of energy systems using CPS completely alters the marginal abatement cost curve (MACC) and creates novel pathways for the transition to a low-carbon energy system. Moreover, the assessment concludes that when CPS are combined with artificial intelligence (AI), decarbonisation could potentially progress at an unforeseeable pace while introducing unpredictable and potentially existential risks. Therefore, the impact of intelligent CPS on systemic resilience and energy security is discussed and policy recommendations are deducted. The assessment shows that the potential benefits clearly outweigh the latent risks as long as these are managed by policy makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Useful Links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cares.cam.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://como.ceb.cam.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Computational Modelling Group, University of Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jparksimulator.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;J-Park Simulator, A Part of The World Avatar Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Cycle Gas Turbine Model for Heat and Power Dispatch Subject to Grid Constraints</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_combined_cycle_dispatch-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 11:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_combined_cycle_dispatch-copy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro-Energy System: A New Discipline fo Energy Transition</title>
      <link>/post/macro-energy-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/macro-energy-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In scientific community, a very question people like to ask each other is “what do you do” or “what is your research about”. Interestingly, every time I said “I work on energy” or something like that, I was in trouble. Depending on the background of your fellow, they may have quite different perspectives on what energy is and what is energy research about: if you are talking to material scientist, they could think energy is all about developing better electrode materials which could result in high-performance batteries; if you are talking to chemist, they might think energy is basically about finding novel catalysts or reaction path which would turn CO2 into fossil fuels (this is exactly my girlfriend does); if you are talking to electric engineers, they might think energy is about resilient power grid which could accommodate more renewable generation; and so on so force. They are all correct in the sense that if they manage to fully unleash their research potential at industrial scale, the energy trilemma could be largely tackled. However, we have to admit that although scientists worldwide have achieved impressive progresses in these domains, the overall landscape of energy conversion and utilization has not changed much since industrial revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/sankey_diagram1.png&#34; alt=&#34;sankey_diagram&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sankey diagram of 2019 energy use in U.S. clearly shows that the bulk of global energy consumption still comes from fossil fuel.However, in pathways limiting global warming to 1.5oC, global total CO2 emission are reduced to net zero around 2050. In such a context, it becomes very important to unleash the potential from intra-system re-innovation, I mean together with fundamental changes of component level performance leap, some priority should be given to system level design and optimization which would make the performance of each single component at their best value. Of course, this is not easy because on one side, the energy system landscape (what technologies are used, how they are designed and operated etc.) has been there for decades with high techno-institutional inertial that are quite difficult to overcome; on the other side, I think this research direction has not been paid much attention compared to other aspects. A key lesson I have learned from my energy system study is the complexity and interdisciplinary nature of energy transition. Factors that can accelerate the decarbonization of energy system are diverse, including industrial bottlenecks (technological challenges, natural resource availability and constraints in material supplies and manufacturing capacity), regulatory limitations, economic forces and fiscal constraints, political constraints and goal, collective action problems, consumer preferences and fears, lack of public acceptance, rational and irrational influences on public and private investment decisions, and others. Solving these intertwined challenges will requires co-analysis of economic, engineering, environmental, and social factors that originated from many fields spanning the natural, social, and engineering, sciences. The chanllenge is amplified by the fact that there is no scientific community that specialized on this topic, energy researchers are from various backgrounds with their own basis, so they only justify the soundness of their disciplinary basis. In a recent paper on &lt;em&gt;Joule&lt;/em&gt;journal, some researchers from Stanford University address this issue. In the paper, they proposed a new terminology for the science of energy transition, which require multi-disciplinary innovations across multi-scale in the energy system landscape. I personally could not agree more and again, I really think promoting systematic analysis in energy transition would be critical for the success of solving such grand chanllenges for human beings. I here call for more attention to this exciting new research area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/macro_energy_system.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;macro_energy_system&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reference&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patricia J. Levi, Simon Davidsson Kurland, Michael Carbajales-Dale, John P. Weyant, Adam R. Brandt, Sally M. Benson, Macro-Energy Systems: Toward a New Discipline, &lt;em&gt;Joule&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 3, Issue 10, 2019, Pages 2282-2286, ISSN 2542-4351, DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2019.07.017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2019.07.017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>/activity/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activity/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ontology framework towards decentralized information management for eco-industrial parks</title>
      <link>/publication/2018_industrial_park_ontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018_industrial_park_ontology/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The critical role of economic assumptions in cost-effectiveness analysis of power plant CO2 capture and storage</title>
      <link>/publication/2018_energy_forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 11:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018_energy_forum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the feature engineering of building energy data mining</title>
      <link>/publication/2018_building_feature_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018_building_feature_engineering/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Plant Decarbonization</title>
      <link>/project/fossil-fuel-power-plant-decarbonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fossil-fuel-power-plant-decarbonization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project presents a novel integrated assessment model by combining bottom-up techno-economic model, metamodel, vintage stock model, and technology learning curve, based on updated aggregated plant-level data. Essentially, this study answers the following questions: What are the practical limits that various techniques could provide in fossil fuel power plant decarbonization (e.g. ton CO2 reduction)? How much are the corresponding change of levelized cost of electricity (e.g. $ per MWh electricity) and CO2 mitigation costs (e.g. $ per ton CO2 reduction)? It is, to the best of our knowledge, the first of its kind fossil power plant decarbonization potential assessment framework under progressive timeline with detailed technology representation and learning curve of individual power plant. It is believed that such approach would bring additional accuracy to the fossil fuel power plant emission accounting, thus shading light on the understanding of how much CO2 emission from fossil fuel power plant are bound to happen over the next decades and the real capability that various decarbonization techniques are able to offer in the stabilization wedges as well as corresponding economic penalties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Useful Links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cares.cam.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://como.ceb.cam.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Computational Modelling Group, University of Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jparksimulator.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;J-Park Simulator, A Part of The World Avatar Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmu.edu/epp/iecm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Integrated Environmental Control Model, Carnegie Mellon University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential Energy Forecast</title>
      <link>/project/residential-energy-use-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/residential-energy-use-forecast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the underlying dynamics of building energy consumption is the very firrst step towards energy saving in building sector; as a powerful tool for knowledge discovery, data mining is being applied to this domain more and more frequently. However, most previous researchers focus on model development during the pipeline of data mining, with feature engineering simply being overlooked. To fill this gap, three different feature engineering approaches, namely Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) as a feature visualization method, Random Forest (RF) as a feature selection method and Principal Component Analysis (PCA) as a feature extraction method, are investigated in the paper. These feature engineering methods are tested with a building energy consumption dataset with 124 features, which describe the building physics, weather condition, and occupant behavior. The 124 features are analyzed and ranked in this paper. It is found that although feature importance depends on specific machine learning model, yet certain features will always dominate the feature space. The outcome of this study favors the usage of effective yet computationally cheap feature engineering methods such as EDA; for other building energy data mining problems, the method proposed by this study has important implications as well because it provides a starting point where effecient feature engineering and machine learning models could be further developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Useful Links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thermalenergysystemslab.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Thermal Energy Systems Lab, Nanyang Technological University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jurong_Island&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jurong Island Eco-Industrial Park, Singapore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pecanstreet.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pecan Street, The Largest Source of Disaggregated Customer Energy and Water Data on The Planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
